Guide to the George P. Garrett Papers, 1929-2008 (bulk 1960-2000)
George P. Garrett papers 1929-2008 (bulk 1960-2000)
- Audiovisual Material Series, 1970-1996 and undated
  - Roundtables and Panels
    - Writers Talking, 1990, Feb. 11, (1 tape)
    - Miami Book Fair, 1990, Nov. 17, (2 tapes)
    - "The Writing Life," 1991, Feb. 17, (1 tape)
    - "Uneasy Muses," 1991, June 8, (1 tape)
    - Pen/Faulkner Awards Gala, 1991, Oct. 7, (1 tape)
    - Pen/Faulkner Awards Gala at Fogler Library, 1991, Nov. 7, (1 tape)
    - Morgan, Robert and Garrett at Writers' Network, 1991, Nov. 16, (3 tapes)
    - "Sources and Resources," 1991, Nov. 23, (1 tape)
    - Class: 1991, (1 tape)
    - McElroy, Colleen and Garrett, 1992, March 6, (1 tape)
    - Humphreys, Josephine and Garrett, 1992, April 24, (1 tape)
    - Staff reading, 1992, July 1, (1 tape)
    - Reading for homeless at UVa, 1992, Sept. 22, (1 tape)
    - Dove, Rita and Garrett: excerpt from reading for homeless, 1992, Sept. 22, (1 tape)
    - Jefferson Scholars and AAUW, 1992, Nov. 2, (1 tape)
    - Chapters Bookstore, 1993, May 27, (1 tape)
    - Blair, Sydney and Garrett, 1993, Oct. 27, (2 tapes)
    - Staff reading, 1993, (1 tape)
    - "Book Reviewing in America," undated, (1 tape)
    - Chappell, Fred and Garrett, undated, (1 tape)
    - Garrett/Democrats, undated, (1 tape)
    - "Enchanted Ground," undated, (1 tape)
    - Huddle, David and Garrett, undated, (1 tape)
    - Taylor, Henry and Garrett, undated, (1 tape)
    - Misc. micro-cassettes, (23 tapes)
    - "Perspiration and Inspiration: The Craft and Vision of Writing," 1992, (12 tapes)
    - Book galley: "Entered from the Sun," 1990, Oct. 31, (1 tape)
    - "The Modern American Novel" and "Literature of WWII," undated, (1 tape)
    - Garrett at Hillsdale College, undated, (1 tape)
    - Garrett: reading at WVCC, 1989, Feb. 21, (1 tape)
    - Panel discussion on creative writing programs at Hollins, 1986, Fall, (1 tape)
    - Garrett at CVCC, 1990, April 5, (1 tape)
    - Prospectus for "Eminent Scholar/Teacher Series," undated, (1 tape)
    - "Author-to-Author: The Fiction of Mary Lee Settle," 1990, (1 tape)
    - "Author-to-Author: First Novelists," 1990, (1 tape)
    - "Author-to-Author; Contemporary Short Story Writers," 1990, (1 tape)
    - "Author-to Author: Contemporary Poets," 1990, (1 tape)
- Miscellaneous Papers Series, circa 1960-1996 and undated
  Chiefly comprised of printed material, clippings, bills and financial papers, schedules, notes, and itineraries.
  - Miscellaneous papers, (19 folders) (Box M 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (12 folders) (Box M 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (22 folders) (Box M 3)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (13 folders) (Box M 4)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (22 folders) (Box M 5)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (17 folders) (Box M 6)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (13 folders) (Box M 7)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (16 folders) (Box M 8)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (17 folders) (Box M 9)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (37 folders) (Box M 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (34 folders) (Box M 11)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (18 folders) (Box M 12)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (7 folders) (Box M 13)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (16 folders) (Box M 14)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (11 folders) (Box M 15)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (14 folders) (Box M 16)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (20 folders) (Box M 17)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (17 folders) (Box M 18)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (12 folders) (Box M 19)
  - Miscellaneous papers, (14 folders) (Box M 20)
- Accession #1998-0356
  This accession of the George Garrett Papers documents the life, career, and writing of the author and educator. The collection spans 1980 to 1998, chiefly 1995-1997, and consists of correspondence, writings (manuscripts, proofs, and drafts), clippings, audiotapes of various authors, including Garrett reading their works, and manuscripts from other authors submitted to Garrett for review and comment. This addition to the existing collection has received minimal processing and is open for research.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    The personal and professional correspondence received by George Garrett between 1995 and 1998, chiefly 1996-1997, documents Garrett's career, professional relationships, and personal relationships with other writers and his students.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, (17 folders)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, (16 folders) (Box 2)
    - Frederick Busch, (1 folder)
    - George Core / Sewanee Review, (1 folder)
    - David Havrid, (1 folder)
    - Jan G. Hensley, (1 folder)
    - LSU Press, (1 folder)
    - Hilary Masters, (1 folder)
    - Philip May, (1 folder)
    - SMU, (1 folder)
    - Elizabeth Spencer, (1 folder)
    - Tom Whalen, (1 folder)
  - Writings (Box 3)
    The Writings Series includes the page proofs, typescripts, and handwritten manuscript pages of Garrett's recent poetry, non-fiction, and novels. Included in this series are several versions of Garrett's novel The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You, as well as his longer non-fiction pieces, Living with Elizabethans, Doing the Literary Thing, and Here and Now. The titles for the manuscript fragments and handwritten drafts were taken from the storage envelopes used by Garrett or are approximated from the text.
    - "Picking and Choosing", (1 folder)
      Page Proofs
    - The King of Babylon, (2 folders)
    - Doing the Literary Thing, (2 folders)
    - Then and There, (3 folders)
    - Living with Elizabethans, (3 folders)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, (8 folders)
      Typescripts of some of Garrett's shorter pieces, reviews, poetry and unidentified manuscript pages.
    - The King of Babylon, (3 folders) (Box 4)
      Typescript - "1st Draft"
    - The King of Babylon, (3 folders)
      Typescript - "Revised 8/28/95"
    - The King of Babylon, (2 folders)
      Typescript - "Original Revised 8/25/95"
    - The King of Babylon, (3 folders)
      Typescript - "2nd Version"
    - Here and Now, (3 folders)
    - Bad Man Blues, (1 folder)
      Page Proofs, 1998
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, (1 folder)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - "It Hums, It Sings, It Dance", (1 folder)
      Handwritten draft
    - "The Pornagraphies", (1 folder)
    - "Alabama: A Perfect Stranger" and "Anecdotes", (1 folder)
      Handwritten draft and typescript
    - "Three Occasional Pieces", (1 folder)
    - "The Long Roll", (1 folder)
    - "Babylon", (1 folder)
    - "Hanging From the Trestle While the Train Goes By", (1 folder)
    - "Babylon - Popular Culture", (1 folder)
    - Miscellaneous Poems, (1 folder)
      Typescripts - "New Poems"
    - "Bad Man Blues", (1 folder)
    - "Part III - Essays", (1 folder)
    - "Heroes", (1 folder)
    - "Whatever Became of the King of Babylon?", (1 folder)
    - "Babylon: The Secret Book of Penrose Weatherby", (1 folder)
    - Letter to the Fellowship of Southern Writers, (1 folder)
    - "Wendell Berry Introduction", (1 folder)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts and Handwritten Drafts, (5 folders)
  - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    The Miscellaneous Series includes the manuscripts written by others submitted to Garrett for review and comment, conference materials, awards, and paperwork relating to Garrett's writing seminars and other classes.
  - Writings (Box 6)
    - "Days of Our Lives", (2 folders)
      Typescript
    - Miscellaneous Drafts and Notes, (8 folders)
    - Review of Playing With Fire
    - The Days of Our Lives Lie in Fragments, (2 folders)
      Page proofs
    - "Perfect Strangers", (1 folder)
      Handwritten manuscript
    - Review - "The Old Oxymoronic Itch...", (1 folder)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Diary, 1985
    - "William Goyen: The Terrible Embrace of Art"
      Texas Review, Page Proofs
    - Royalty Statements
    - Name Tags and Conference Materials
    - Farewell, I'm Bound to Leave You, by Fred Chappell, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - The Madhouse Nudes, by Robert Schultz, 1996, (1 folder)
    - Hero, by Robert Dillen, (1 folder)
    - "Poetry Anthology", (1 folder)
    - Extreme Justice, by Vincent S. Green, (1 folder)
    - Swimming in the Congo, by Margaret Meyers, (1 folder)
    - Black Transit, by Tom Alderson, (3 folders)
    - Señora Honeycomb, by Margaret Sayer Penden, (1 folder)
    - Circling, by Paul Ruffin, (1 folder)
    - Just Here, Just Now, by R.H.W. Dillard, (1 folder)
    - The Leap, by Sebastian Rotella, (2 folders)
    - Hotel Malabar, by Brendan Galvin, (1 folder)
    - Daytime and Starlight, by James Appelwhite, (1 folder)
    - Jack Horner in Love and War, by R.V. Cassill, (2 folders)
    - The White Rooster and Other Stories, by Robert Bausch, (1 folder)
    - The Tent of Orange Mist, by Paul West, (1 folder)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, (2 folders)
  - Clippings, (13 folders) (Box 8)
    The Clippings Series includes newspaper and magazine clippings, flyers for reading and other events, publisher catalogs, and other promotional materials.
  - Audio Cassettes (Box 9)
    Tapes of readings and speeches by George Garrett and others, 1980-1996, and undated The titles for the tapes were established by Garrett. An alphabetical (by reader) list of tapes follows and is enclosed with the cassettes.
    - Unidentified
      - "Intro to Nims"
      - Enchanted Ground, 1980
      - Fellowship of Southern Writers, Uva, 1996
      - Fiction Reading, Johns Hopkins, 1996
      - New Letters on the Air
    - Award
      - Frederick Wiseman Documentary, VA Festival of American Film, 1988
    - Battestin, Martin
      - Interview
    - Battestin, Martin and Ruthe
      - Talks, 1995
    - Bausch,; Garrett,; Bloom
      - Wesleyan/Presbyterian Readings
    - Bausch, Richard and Robert
      - Reading, UVA, 1988
    - Bausch, Richard and George Garrett
      - Reading, Bennington, VT, 1996
    - Berry, Wendel l and Henry Taylor
      - Aiken-Taylor Awards, Sewanee, TN
    - Blair,; Casey,; Eisenberg,; Garrett,; Settle
      - "Our Place," Virgina Festival of the Book, 1995
    - Blair, Sydney,; Debra Nystrom
      - Reading, 1992
    - Brown, Rita Mae;; George Garrett;; Ann Beattie;; Eudora Welt y
      - Literacy Reading, UVA, 1988
    - Buechner, Frederick (2 cassettes)
      - Reading, UVA
      - Reading from Son of Laughter, UVA
    - Chandler, Marilyn;; George Garrett;; Diane Johnson
      - Varieties of Literary Biography
    - Chappell, Fred;; George Garrett ( Wilma Dykeman, moderator)
      - Book & Author Dinner, Knoxville, TN, 1989
    - Cheuse, Alan
      - Reading
    - Chute, Caroline;; Maggie Anderson
      - Hollins Literary Festival
    - Ciardi, John
      - "Speaking of Words," National Public Radio
    - Cooley, Nicole;; Tom Whalen;; George Garrett
      - Reading, Wurzburg, 1996
    - Crews, Harry (2 cassettes)
      - "A Childhood: A Biography," American Audio Prose Library
      - Interview, American Audio Prose Library
    - Dillard, R.H.W. (2 Cassettes)
      - Reading, Mary Bladwin College
      - Reading, UVA, 1992
    - Douglas, Ellen (2 cassettes)
      - Hollins Literary Festival, 1995
      - Reading, UVA, 1995
    - Drury, Tom;; Vivian Gornick;; Henry Taylor
      - Reading, Weslyan, 1995
    - Earley, Tony;; Brooks Haxton
      - Hollins Literary Festival, 1995
    - Engels, John;; Lucy Ferris
      - Reading, Hollins College, 1996
    - Galvin, Brendan (2 cassettes)
      - Reading, Hollins College, 1990
      - Reading, Williams Corner Bookstore
    - Garrett, George (62 cassettes)
      - "Art & Craft of Mary Lee Settle," Auburn, 1988
      - "Conclusion"
      - "Garrett at Large," Jacksonville, FL, 1991
      - "Uncles and Others," Arkansas State, 1988
      - Bonfire of the Vanities Lecture, 1991
      - Friends of the Library Lecture, 1991
      - Interview, American Audio Prose Library
      - Jefferson Society Address, UVA
      - Reading undated
      - Reading 4/5/90
      - Reading, American Audio Prose, Lib.
      - Reading, Borders Bookstore
      - Reading, Brentano's NYC, 1992
      - Reading, Eastern Washington University
      - Reading, Emory, 1992
      - Reading, Farmington CC, 1991
      - Reading, Hampden-Sydney College, 1991
      - Reading, Johns Hopkins, 1996
      - Reading, Loudon Lib. 1995
      - Reading, Presbyterian College, 1995
      - Reading, Regulator/ Chapters, 1996
      - Reading, Second Street Gallery, 1992
      - Reading, St. Pauls, VA, 1994
      - Reading, The Gallery UVA, 1992
      - Reading, VMI, 1990
      - Reading, Williams Corner Bookstore, 1996
      - Reading, Williams Corner Bookstore, 1993
      - Reading at Barnes and Noble, Charlottesville, 1995
      - Reading at Executive Mansion, Charleston, WV, 1993
      - Reading at the Rotunda, UVA, 1995
      - Reading from King of Babylon..., Williams Corner Bookstore, 1995
      - Reading, Quartz Mountain, 1990
      - Reading, Orlando Library, 1990
      - Speaking to Alumni Associates, Roanoke, 1993
      - Speech, Southern University Press, 1996
      - Talk & Introduction, Atlanta, 1996
      - Talk about "Babette's Feast," 1995
      - Talk on Reading, 1990s
      - Talk on May Sarton, Virginia Beach, 1994
      - Talk to Friends of Library, VCU
      - Talking to Class, 2nd Street, Randolph Macon
      - Reading with others, Chapters Bookstore
      - Reading, Alan Cheuse Intro., 1995
      - Reading, Bausch and Bell intro. Chapters/ Rizzoli
      - Reading, Geoff Clark Intro. Roger Williams University, 1995
      - Reading, Henry Taylor, S tephen Sands Intro., Aspen/Harvard, 1987
      - Reading, Josh Wheeler, intro., 1995
      - Reading, Mary Flinn intro., AAUW
      - Reading, Meghan Gehman intro., Randolph Macon
      - Reading, R.H.W. Dillard intro., Hollins College, 1996
      - Reading from Poison Pen, R.H.W. Dillard intro., Hollins College, 1986
      - PEN/Malamud Award, Folder Library, 1990
      - Reading, Richard Bausch intro. 1996
      - Reading, Richard Bausch intro., Folger Lib. 1990
      - Reading, Richard Bausch intro. Loudon Cty. Lib. 1995
      - Reading, Sydney Blair intro. 1996
      - MFA Reading, UVA, 1995
      - On "The Succession" with actors
      - Reading, with Josephine Humphreys,; Converse College, 1992
      - Reading, with Richard Bausch, Amy Bloom, Wesleyan University, 1995
      - Reading, with William Warfiel d
      - The Writing Life, with Menshew,; Bausch,; Blair, Orr, 1991
    - Giardina, Denise;; Maggie Anderson
      - Hollins Literary Festival
    - Goldsmith, Rev. Maurice L.
      - Reading, 1996
    - Grealy, Lucy;; Meg Wolitzer
      - Reading, Bennington, VT, 1996
    - Gurganus, Alan;; George Garrett,; Darden A Pryon
      - Miami Book Fair, 1990
    - Harris, Wilson
      - Reading, UVA, 1988
    - Honrburg, Michae l
      - Reading from Bongwater, UVA, 1995
    - Humphreys, Josephine;; George Garrett;; Padgett Powell
      - "Story: Sources and Resources," 1991
    - Indian Writers; Kit Reed intro.
      - Reading, Hollins College, 1992
    - Induction of William Faulkner and Wallace Stevens
      - Poet's Corner Vespers Service, St. John the Devine, NYC, 1989
    - Johnson, Denis
      - Reading, UVA, 1996
    - Kennedy, Gerta
      - Reading, Johnson State College
    - Kimball, Philip
      - Reading, Johnson State College, 1977, 1978
    - Matthiessen, Pete r
      - Reading, UVA
    - McLaurin, Tim;; George Garrett
      - Reading, Chatam Hall, 1992
    - Moody, Rick;; Elizabeth Cox;; Michael Curtis
      - Reading, Bennington, VT, 1996
    - National Public Radio
      - "Wedding Cake Stories"
    - O'Connor, Flannery;; Frank Sinatra
      - "Flannery and Frank"
    - Pen/Faulkner Awards Gala
      - "Heroes," 1991
    - Princeton University Alumni Seminar
      - "Uneasy Mess"
    - Rector, Liam;; Ed Ochester;; Jonathan Holden
      - Bennington, VT, 1996
    - Settle, Mary Lee (2 cassettes)
      - VA Festival of the Book, 1996
    - Settle, Mary Lee;; George Garrett;; Alan Cheuse
      - VFH Reading, 1995
    - Settle, Mary Lee;; John Casey;; Jeanne Larse n; Henry Taylor
      - Writers Talking, UVA, 1994
    - Simpson, Mona;; Jay MacInerny
      - Bennington, VT, 1987
    - Smith, Ron;; Ann Freeman
      - The Gallery, 1989
    - Stone, Robert with George Garrett intro.
      - UVA, 1996
    - Taylor, Henry (5 cassettes)
      - "Landscape with Tractor"
      - Autobiography Conference, with Fred Chappell, Conway, AK
      - Reading with Fred Chappell, University of Central AK
      - Reading with George Garrett, VCU, 1988
      - Virginia Festival of the Book, with Rita Dove, 1996
    - Vaughn, Betsy;; Henry Taylor
      - Hollins Literary Festival, 1994
    - Virginia Festival of American Film
      - Screenplay Panel, Henry Taylo r, moderator, UVA, 1988
    - Wesleyan Writers Conference
      - Staff Reading, 1987
    - Wier, Allen
      - Hollins Literary Festival, 1996
    - McGarry, Jean;; Stephen Dixon
      - Johns Hopkins, 1996
    - Wilbur, Richard
      - Bennington College, 1987
  - Video Cassette
    - The Great Gatsby - The Discovery Channel, 9/13/1997
  - Published Materials (Box 10)
    Proofs, galleys, and reader's pre-publication copies of works of fiction and non-fiction by various authors; literary journals, anthologies; and published works by Garrett and others.
    - Dictionary of Literary Biography, Cumulative Index, 1997
    - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You
      Uncorrected Proof
    - All Soul's Rising, by Madison Smart Bell
      Advance Readers Copy
    - The Sewanee Review
      Vol. CII (3): Summer 1995
    - A Dead Man in Deptford, by Anthony Burgess
      Advance Reading Copy
    - Virginia Quarterly Review
      Vol. 72 (3): Summer 1996
    - The Physician of London, by Stephanie Cowel l
      Uncorrected Proof Copy
    - The Texas Review
      Vol. XV (3 & 4): Fall/Winter 1994
    - Bongwater, by Michael Hornburg
      Advance Uncorrected Proof
    - The Whole Story: Editors of Fiction, edited by Warren Slesinger
    - Wartime, by Paul Fussell
    - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You, by George Garrett
      Harcourt Brace, 1998
    - Days of Our Lives Lie in Fragments: New and Old Poems, by George Garrett
      LSU Press, 1998, cloth
    - Days of Our Lives Lie in Fragments: New and Old Poems, by George Garrett
      LSU Press, 1998, paperback
    - Manchu Palaces, by Jeanne Larsen
    - Witness
      Vol. X (2): 1996
    - Anthology of the Poetry Society of Virginia, 1993
    - Contemporary Southern Poetry: An Anthology, 1980
    - River City: A Journal of Contemporary Culture
      Summer, 1998
    - Black Warrior Review
      Vol. XXII (1): Fall/Winter 1995(2 copies)
    - The Golden Rope, by Susan Fromberg Schaeffer
    - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You, by George Garrett
    - Growing Up Southern: How the South Shapes its Writers, edited by Fred Brown and J eanne McDonald
      Blue Ridge Publishing, 1997
    - The Influence of William Faulkner, by George Garrett
      reprint from The Georgia Review, Vol. XVII (4): Winter 1964
    - "LILT"
      Pinch Press, 1994; Number 62 of an edition of 250,
  - Promotional Materials (Opaperfolder Folder 1)
    Oversize posters and flyers
- Accession (1999-0268)
  This addition to the collection consists of a photocopy of a typed draft of Garrett's novel The King of Babylon Shall Not Come against You ( 1996?). There are handwritten annotations.
  - (Box 1)
- Accession (1999-0379)
  The materials cover the date span 1956-1972. Some short writings are interfiled or attached to letters.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - A-B, 1963-1972
    - C-D, 1962-1972
    - E-G, 1957-1972
    - H-J, 1962-1972 and undated
    - K-L, 1964-1972
    - M, 1963-1972
    - Unsorted correspondence and miscellaneous items (3 folders) (Box 2)
- Accession (2000-0085)
  This group of materials (1964-1999) includes drafts and published versions of Garrett's works, literary correspondence, audiotapes of readings by Garrett and others, clippings, and other items further documenting his literary career. Items often relate to his publication, The King Of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You.
  - Correspondence
    - Personal and Professional Correspondence with Bill Peden and Sharon Hagin, 1964-1978 (11 folders) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-1998 (9 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1999 (16 folders) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995-1999 (18 folders) (Box 3)
  - Writings
    - Miscellaneous writings and clippings, 1993 and undated (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous holograph writings (Box 4)
      Titles are noted when found and materials were kept in order, although it was rarely clear just where one writing ended and another began.
      - Billy Tone has an Opinion Too, Interview at Weatherby House, and Jojo's Joke
      - Inserts
      - Babylon
      - Talking with Sheriff Dale Lewis, and Spilling the Beans: A Letter to Linda Evangelista
      - Babylon mss.
      - Misc. pages
      - Typing for Babylon
      - Pictures -- The Saw Mill, and A Well-Kept Secret typing for King of Babylon
      - Proof
      - The King of Babylon -- early version
      - Cease Firing [Garrett- Disk 001 was removed from same envelope as this ms., and data copied to server. See staff for assistance.]
      - Change
      - Cuts from Babylon
      - Billy Tone Writes to a Friend and Creditor
    - Typescripts
      - Child Among Ancestors [unpublished?] (4 folders)
      - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You: An Oral History for Imaginary Voices (5 folders)
    - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You, bound proof
    - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You, Earlier Version -- Second/Third Draft, typescript (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - Yellow Shoe Poets, final proof copy (4 folders)
    - Holograph manuscript
    - Printed materials -- primarily journals, 1978-1999 (17 volumes)
    - Holograph manuscripts by Garrett (14 folders) (Box 6)
    - Other writings primarily by Garrett (12 folders)
  - Printed Materials (Box 7)
    Contains publications with pieces by Garrett, some writings by others, reviews of Garrett's work, book catalogs, and additional miscellaneous printed items. It appears Garrett folded back pages in certain pieces to the page where his writing began or where he was written about. Most items were closed and flags were placed to show the page where Garrett had marked them.
    - Oedipus at Colonus
    - Book Reviewing in America (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous (14 folders)
    - Miscellaneous (7 folders and 16 volumes) (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1997 (10 folders and 10 volumes) (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Audio recordings of classes and readings (23 cassettes)
    - Conference and ID badges
  - Clippings
    - Clippings (5 folders) (Box 10)
      Includes a number of reviews for The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You
  - Oversize Materials
    - Primarily clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 11)
- Accession (2000-0303)
  - The King of Babylon Shall Not Come Against You, 1995, revised typescript and page proofs (Box 1)
  - Entered From the Sun, undated, revised typescript (Box 2)
  - Writers--East of the Blue Ridge, videotape
  - Cassette tapes of readings and lectures, (11 cassettes) (Box 3)
- Accession (2002-0034)
  Addition (1 item, 1 lin. ft.; dated 2002) comprises an uncorrected page proof, with color cover, for Garrett's Going to See the Elephant: Pieces of a Writing Life. This accession is unprocessed and is interfiled.
- Accessions (2004-0133) and (2005-0067), 5 Boxes